spaceflightinsider.com 2019-09-04

# Privacy Policy - SpaceFlight Insider

Last updated on November 21st, 2018

We consider the privacy of our visitors to be extremely important. This privacy policy describes how information is collected, used and disclosed by SpaceFlight Insider (“us”, “we”, or “our”), and applies to information we collect when you use or access www.spaceflightinsider.com (the “Site”). We use this information only to provide and improve the Site. By using the Site, you agree to the collection and usage of information in accordance with this policy.

SpaceFlight Insider may change this policy by updating this page.

### Contact

If you require additional information or have any questions regarding our privacy policy, please feel free to contact us at [spaceflightinsider@gmail.com](mailto:spaceflightinsider@gmail.com).

### We may collect information in the following ways

  * Through the use of cookies
  * Through forms filled out by a user on the Site
  * Through the maintenance and analysis of web technical server log files
  * Via e-mail and other communications between a user of the Site

### Log Files

Our Site makes use of technical server log files to improve user experience. The information collected in these log files may include Internet Protocol addresses, internet service providers, browser types, browser versions, referring pages, the date and time of your visit(s), the duration of your visit(s), and the page(s) of our Site that you visit. The information gathered in these log files is not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

### Cookies

“Cookies” are files containing small amounts of data, which may include anonymous unique identifiers. Cookies are sent to your browser from the Site or our advertising and analytics partners and stored on your computer.

We use cookies to personalize content and ads, to provide social media features and to analyze our traffic. We also share information about your use of our Site with our social media, advertising and analytics partners, who may combine it with other information you’ve provided to them or they’ve collected from your use of their services.

SpaceFlight Insider may also collect non-personally identifiable information from users via cookies, server log data and other similar technological means. Such information may be used to track site performance and enhance the user experience, and may be shared with trusted third parties.

Third party vendors may use cookies to serve ads based on prior visits to the Site or other websites. To the extent third parties may place advertising on the Site, such third parties may utilize cookies or other technological means within the advertising to collect and utilize non-personally identifiable information. SpaceFlight Insider is not responsible for information collected by third parties in this manner, nor for the collection or use of information by other sites to which the Site is linked.

You may instruct your browser to refuse cookies. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Site.

### Our Analytics Partners

We use third party analytics partners to help analyze how visitors use the Site. Our analytics partners include Google, Inc. (“Google”) and Automattic Inc. (“Jetpack” or “Automattic”). Each of these analytics partners maintains their own privacy policy. You should consult the respective policies of these third-parties for more detailed information on their practices.

**Google Analytics Cookies and Privacy**

  * Google Analytics uses cookies to report on visitor interactions on the Site.
  * Google Analytics may additionally collect Internet Protocol addresses to determine the country, state, or city of visitors.
  * Visitors may opt out of Google Analytics by following the instructions in Google’s Analytics privacy policy. Google’s Analytics privacy policy can be reviewed at the following location: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>

**Jetpack / Automattic Cookies and Privacy**

  * Automattic may collect a visitor’s Internet Protocol address, WordPress.com user ID and/or username (if logged in), browser type, browser language, visiting URL, referring URL, timestamp of event, and country code. This information is not made available to us and is only retained by Automattic for 28 days.
  * Automattic may also track page views, video plays, outbound links, referring URLs, search engine terms, and the visitor’s country.
  * Automattic’s privacy policy can be reviewed at the following location: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>

### Our Advertising Partners

Some of our third party advertising partners may use cookies and web beacons on our site. Our advertising partners include Google, Inc. (“Google”) and Sovrn Holdings, Inc. (“Sovrn” or “Lijit”). Each of these advertising partners maintains their own privacy policy. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-parties for more detailed information on their practices.

**Google / DoubleClick Cookies and Privacy**

  * Google, as a third party vendor, uses the DoubleClick cookie to serve ads on the Site.
  * Google’s use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it to serve ads to visitors of the Site based upon their past visit(s) to the Site and other site(s) on the Internet.
  * Users may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick cookie by visiting Google’s [Ad Settings](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences).
  * Google’s privacy policy can be reviewed at the following location: <https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/ads/>

**Sovrn / Lijit Cookies and Privacy**

  * Sovrn collects anonymous site visit data.
  * Sovrn collects only anonymous information unless a reader chooses to submit personal information to Sovrn.
  * Users may opt out of this anonymous data collection by installing the Lijit “opt-out” cookie. [Click here](http://info.evidon.com/pub_info/2672?v=1&nt=0&nw=false) to install this cookie.
  * Sovrn’s privacy policy can be reviewed at the following location: <https://www.sovrn.com/privacy-policy/>

### Use of Information

SpaceFlight Insider may use information collected in connection with the Site in the following manner:

  * To improve user experience while using the Site.
  * To provide requested information, products and services to users via the Site or through other online or offline channels.
  * Internal record keeping.

In order to do the foregoing, SpaceFlight Insider may provide the information to trusted third parties, including but not limited to selected third party marketers and vendors as well as third party contractors providing services such as the operation of the Site, communication services and information verification. SpaceFlight Insider will use reasonable efforts to limit use of the information by such third parties to the specific uses set forth above. SpaceFlight Insider also uses electronic and physical security to reduce the risk of improper access to or manipulation of information during transmission and storage, but cannot guarantee the security or integrity of the information and shall have no liability for breaches of security or integrity or third-party interception in transit. SpaceFlight Insider may also disclose information when it determines it is necessary to comply with applicable laws or regulations, in connection with a merger, acquisition, asset purchase or sale of or by SpaceFlight Insider, or to protect SpaceFlight Insider’s interests or safety, our customers, or other visitors to the Site.

### Online Privacy Policy Only

This privacy policy applies only to our online activities and is valid for visitors to our Site and regarding information shared and/or collected there. This policy does not apply to any information collected offline or via channels other than this Site.

### Consent

By using our Site, you hereby consent to our privacy policy and agree to its terms.
